orvis.com 2011-10-07

# Orvis Privacy Policy

Welcome to the Orvis website. Because your privacy is very important to us, we want you to understand our practices with regard to collecting and using your information both online and offline and the steps we take to safeguard it. This statement applies to personally identifiable information collected from our customers. When this Privacy Policy uses the term "personally identifiable information," we mean information that identifies a particular individual, such as the individual’s name, postal address, e-mail address, credit card number, and telephone number. When other information, such as, for example, consumer product preferences, or number of children, is directly associated with personally identifiable information, this other information also becomes personally identifiable information for purposes of this Privacy Policy. Personally identifiable information is sometimes referred to in this Privacy Policy as "personal information." 

We welcome any and all questions and feedback. For privacy-related issues, please contact us at: 

The Orvis Company  
Attn: Customer Service: 1711 Blue Hills Drive, Roanoke, VA 24012  
888-235-9763  

Information We Collect 

a. Personally Identifiable Information 

We may collect personally Identifiable Information (including name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and, when necessary, credit card information) when you: 

  * Place an order from our catalogs or on our Web site 
  * Make a purchase at one of our retail stores 
  * Return an item or make an exchange 
  * Inquire about our services 
  * Request a catalog 
  * Receive a gift package 
  * Create an account at Orvis.com 
  * Subscribe to our E-mail Newsletter 
  * Enter a contest or sweepstakes 
  * Participate in a marketing survey, promotion or event either online or offline. 

b. Aggregate Information 

Our website collects some non-personal information about you using clickstream technology, so it may not be readily apparent to you that it is being collected. For instance, when you come to our site your IP address is collected. 

An IP address is often associated with the place from which you enter the Internet like your ISP (Internet service provider), your company, or your university. 

This information is not personally identifiable and we do not combine this type of information with personally identifiable information. 

Use of Data We Collect 

a. Personally Identifiable Information 

At Orvis, we always want to provide you with the best possible shopping experience and fulfill your orders exactly as you've requested. In order to do this, we use your personally identifiable information to allow us to: 

  * Process and track your order 
  * Provide the services you request 
  * Contact you about the status of an order 
  * Send you catalogs or promotional offers we believe will be of interest to you 
  * Send you the Orvis E-mail Newsletter, if you specifically request it 
  * Identify your product and service preferences 
  * Customize our communications to you 
  * Provide information concerning product recalls or products you have purchased 
  * Improve our merchandise selection and customer service 
  * Administer a sweepstakes or similar promotion and identify or publicize the winner(s) in accordance with the rules for that promotion.

Your e-mail address will be used only for the Orvis E-mail Newsletter and will not be shared with any third parties, except as described below. Instructions for unsubscribing are included in every e-mail. 

b. Aggregate Information 

We use the aggregate information that we collect from our customers in a manner that does not personally identify any individual. We use aggregate information to make our sites more interesting and useful to you. We also track the pages or documents accessed within our site. This information is collected for systems administration and for analyzing and improving the value of the material available on our website. This aggregate non-personal information is used to help our advertisers or our site design team create advertisements our guests might like.

Orvis contracts with Coremetrics, an outside service that helps us better understand your use of orvis.com. Coremetrics places cookies on your computer so we can collect information related to your use of orvis.com. This information allows us to refine and improve the site for our customers. Coremetrics does NOT collect any credit card, user name or password information or any other personally identifiable information nor are they allowed to use data that they collect for us for any other purpose. Additionally, Coremetrics is contractually required to keep all the information collected for us in strict confidence. 

As a visitor to orvis.com, you may "opt out" of Coremetrics' collection of data. To learn more about your Coremetrics options go to <http://www.coremetrics.com/info_eluminate2.html>. 

Information We Share with Others 

a. Our Contractors 

We contract with other companies (credit card processors, shippers, sweepstakes promoters, website developers and others) to provide certain services to Orvis to fulfill orders, provide sweepstakes and create or maintain our website. In some instances, these contractors may have access to personally identifiable information but they contractually obligated to maintain the confidentiality of the information and to use it only for purposes of carrying out Orvis business. 

These companies are usually prohibited by contract from using this information for their own marketing purposes or from sharing this information with anyone other than Orvis. For example, when you submit a “product review” to the Orvis website, your information will be received and managed by an independent contractor that organizes the reviews and manages that element of the Orvis website. Before you submit a review, you should review the “Terms of Use” and “Standards for Reviews” that are linked on the Orvis website so that you can understand the terms and conditions for acceptance and use of your information. 

In some instances, you may choose to deal with some of these contractors directly and provide your personal information to them. In those instances, you should check the privacy policies on their independent websites to make sure you are willing to have your personal information handled to your satisfaction. 

For example, when you make a purchase from Orvis with a credit card, you may choose to use an independent card processor, such as Google Checkout, or a particular form of credit, such as Bill Me Later (“BML”). When these or similar choices are available, you will be notified about the option of checking their respective privacy policies, which will govern the collection and use of personal information that you give to them directly. 

b. Third Parties 

i. Postal Mailing Partners 

From time to time, we make our postal mailing list (names and postal addresses only) available to carefully screened companies whose products we believe will be of interest to you. If you prefer that we do not share any information with these companies, complete the following form.

You may also make this request by mail by writing us at the following address:

The Orvis Company  
Attn: Customer Service: 1711 Blue Hills Drive, Roanoke, VA 24012  
888-235-9763 

ii. Web Advertising Partners 

We may also share your personally-identifiable information, including your name, address, e-mail address, as well as a record of any transactions you conduct on our website or offline with us, with a third-party advertising partner that we contract with, and its service providers, in order to deliver banner advertisements and other advertising tailored to your interests when you visit certain websites. In these instances, it will use the data we provide it anonymously, that is, without any of your identifying information. Our advertising partner is able to do this, in part, by using “cookies” to collect anonymous information about your visits to our Website, and your interaction with our products and services. As with the information we provide, no personally identifiable information is collected in this process and no personal information will be shared further with any other party. To choose not to have this information used by our third-party advertising partner, [click here](http://usucmweb.dotomi.com/2182/optout.html).

Your e-mail address is never shared with any third party (except as described above to our contractors who use it ONLY to carry out Orvis business and our advertising partner, also as described above.) 

Disclosure Exceptions 

Notwithstanding the above policies, we reserve the right to disclose your personal information to appropriate third parties if we are required to do so by law or we believe that such action is necessary: 

  * To comply with legal process such as a search warrant, subpoena or court order; 
  * To protect the company's rights and property; 
  * To investigate reports of fraud or of users sending material using a false e-mail address or users sending harassing, threatening, or abusive messages; 
  * To protect against misuse or unauthorized use of our web site; or 
  * During emergencies, such as when we believe someone's physical safety is at risk 

****Your Choices

We offer choices about the types of information you receive from us. If you prefer not to receive catalogs or other communications from Orvis or if you prefer to receive them less frequently, use the following form to request a change or cancellation in your catalog mailing subscription. If you no longer wish to receive our E-mail Newsletter, you may unsubscribe online, or unsubscribe using the link provided in each edition of the e-mail. 

You may also make a subscription change or cancellation request for catalogs or E-mail newsletters by mail, by writing to us at the following address: 

The Orvis Company  
Attn: Customer Service: 1711 Blue Hills Drive, Roanoke, VA 24012  
888-235-9763  

Please be sure to provide us your _exact name and address, or the mailing label from your catalog_ , so that we can be sure to identify you correctly. Because mailings are planned in advance, it may take several weeks for your request to become effective. If, due to human error, you continue to receive unwanted communications, please contact us again and we will make every effort to correct the situation. 

E-mail Use 

When you provide us your e-mail address, we may send you e-mails necessary to process your order or respond to a request, or, if you agree to it, to receive or E-mail Newsletter. For example, after you place an order at orvis.com, you will receive an e-mail confirmation and, in most cases, an e-mail with package tracking information. Recipients of our Electronic Gift Certificates will receive an e-mail notifying them of the gift and instructing them how to redeem it. 

It is our intent to send you promotional e-mail (our E-mail Newsletter) only if you have agreed to receive it. Instructions on how to unsubscribe are included in each edition of the newsletter. 

Your e-mail address will be used only for the Orvis E-mail Newsletter, respond to your request or to process your order, and will not be shared with any third parties. Instructions for unsubscribing are included in every e-mail containing promotional material.

Links to Other Sites 

Occasionally we provide links on our web site to other sites we think you will enjoy. These sites operate independently of Orvis and have established their own privacy and security policies. Orvis does not have any control over these sites’ privacy practices. For the best online experience, we strongly encourage you to review these policies at any site you visit. 

Security 

It is our intent to protect against the loss, misuse or alteration of information that we have collected from you. We use a variety of current technologies and processes for protection of our customer data. We limit the information we provide to outside companies with whom we contract to only what they need to carry out their responsibilities. 

When you make a purchase, request a catalog or create an account on our web site, your transactional information is transmitted in a safe, encrypted format. We maintain the data you provide, along with a record of your purchases, in a secure database. To best serve you, we may combine this information with data that is publicly available and data that we receive from other reputable sources whose policies meet the Direct Marketing Association's Privacy Promise; more information can be found at <http://www.dmaconsumers.org/privacy.html>. 

Privacy of Children on Our Web Site 

Our web site is not intended for use by children under the age of 13, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children under the age of 13. 

Policy Changes 

From time to time, we may use customer information for unanticipated uses not previously disclosed in our privacy notice. If our information practices change, we will post these changes on our web site. We encourage you to review our privacy policy periodically. 

This policy was last updated on October 22, 2008. 

Questions or Comments? 

For questions, comments or assistance, we invite you to contact us: 

The Orvis Company  
Attn: Customer Service: 1711 Blue Hills Drive, Roanoke, VA 24012  
888-235-9763  

Additional Topics of Interest

In addition to our Privacy Policy, read our E-Mail Usage Policy and our Website Terms and Conditions. 

Back to Previous Page
